Finding Aid for James B. Griffin Papers 1922-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Correspondence, 1975-1997
  Despite being officially retired, Griffin remained active in the Museum of Anthropology for a number of years, and, particularly in his correspondence with museum administrators Richard Ford, Henry Wright and John Speth, the series reflects his continuing participation in its promotion and development. Much of his focus turned to pursuits outside the University of Michigan, however. For a great deal of this later period, Griffin held a resident research associate position at the Smithsonian Institution in Washington D.C. Much of the correspondence in this series concerns publications he wrote, edited or for which he provided editorial advice, conferences and meetings in which he participated, advising to dissertation writers, and consulting he provided either on his own or as a representative of the Smithsonian. The correspondence also serves as a testament to Griffin's many continuing professional friendships, with substantial accumulations of letters from Stephen Williams, Dan Morse, Anna Roosevelt, Penelope Drooker, N'omi Greber, and a number of others.
  - Adams, Robert McCormick, 1976-1991 (Box 28)
  - Adovasio, J.M., 1977-1987 (Box 28)
  - Agogino, George, 1976-1978 (Box 28)
  - Altuna, Linda M., 1984 (Box 28)
  - Ambrosino, Michael, 1976-1980 (Box 28)
  - Anderson, David G., 1981-1994 (Box 28)
  - Anderson, Duane C., 1976-1986 (Box 28)
  - A -- Miscellaneous (Box 28)
  - Baldia, Maximilian O., 1980-1981 (Box 28)
  - Bareis, Charles, 1976-1993 (Box 28)
  - Barker, Alex, 1990-1993 (Box 28)
  - Bastian, Tyler, 1985-1995 (Box 28)
  - Bell, Robert E., 1976-1983 (Box 28)
  - Bense, Judy, 1993-1994 (Box 28)
  - Bettarel, Robert, 1977-1978 (Box 28)
  - Bird, Junius B., 1978-1983 (Box 28)
  - Braidwood, Robert, 1976 (Box 28)
  - Brain, Jeffrey P., 1977-1985 (Box 28)
  - Braun, David, 1976-1982 (Box 28)
  - Brodkey, Dale, 1976-1977 (Box 28)
  - Brookes, Samuel, 1976-1996 (Box 28)
  - Brose, David S., 1976-1995 (Box 28)
  - Brown, Ian, 1976-1995 (Box 28)
  - Brown, James A., 1976-1995 (Box 28)
  - Bryan, Alan L., 1976-1978 (Box 28)
  - Buettner-Janusch, John, 1953-1974 (Box 28)
  - Buikstra, Jane, 1975-1997 (Box 28)
  - Butler, Brian M., 1978-1985 (Box 28)
  - B -- Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Cantwell, Anne-Marie, 1979-1995 (Box 28)
  - Carlson, John B., 1980-1982 (Box 28)
  - Chapman, Carl, 1976-1984 (Box 28)
  - Chapman, Jefferson, 1976-1990 (Box 28)
  - Chapman, John, 1984-1992 (Box 28)
  - Christenson, Andrew L., 1976-1994 (Box 28)
  - Clay, Berle, 1976-1983 (Box 28)
  - Close, Angela, 1989-1997 (Box 28)
  - Coe, Joffre, 1981-1990 (Box 28)
  - Conklin, Harold C., 1976-1977 (Box 28)
  - Conrad, Lawrence A., 1981-1983 (Box 28)
  - Cowan, C. Wesley, 1976-1986 (Box 28)
  - Custer, Jay, 1985-1992 (Box 28)
  - C -- Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Dancey, William S., 1977-1997 (Box 28)
  - Davis, E. Mott, 1976-1990 (Box 28)
  - Davis, Hester, 1976-1997 (Box 28)
  - de Laguna, Frederica, 1976-1977 (Box 28)
  - de Lumley, Henry, 1975-1977 (Box 28)
  - DeJarnette, David L., 1976 (Box 28)
  - DeVore, Irven, 1983-1988 (Box 28)
  - Di Peso, Charles C., 1976-1977 (Box 28)
  - Dickens, Roy S., 1979-1984 (Box 28)
  - Drennan, Robert D., 1976-1977 (Box 28)
  - Drooker, Penelope, 1988-1997; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Dunn, Mary Eubanks, 1977-1983 (Box 29)
  - Dunnell, Robert C., 1976-1996 (Box 29)
  - Dye, David H., 1976-1989 (Box 29)
  - D -- Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  - Eggan, Fred R., 1976-1986 (Box 29)
  - Emerson, Thomas E., 1982-1995 (Box 29)
  - Engelbrecht, William, 1976-1977 (Box 29)
  - Essenpreis, Patricia S., 1980-1986 (Box 29)
  - Evans, Clifford, 1976-1979 (Box 29)
  - Eyman, Charles E., 1977-1979 (Box 29)
  - Eyre, J.D., 1986-1987 (Box 29)
  - E -- Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  - Fagan, Brian M., 1976-1977 (Box 29)
  - Fagette, Paul, 1982-1995 (Box 29)
  - Fairbanks, Charles H., 1976-1985 (Box 29)
  - Farnsworth, Kenneth B., 1976-1992 (Box 29)
  - Faulkner, Charles H., 1975-1988 (Box 29)
  - Flanders, Richard E., 1982-1990 (Box 29)
  - Fogelson, Raymond D., 1976-1983 (Box 29)
  - Ford, Richard I., 1977-1992 (Box 29)
  - Fowler, Melvin L., 1976-1981 (Box 29)
  - Freimuth, Glen, 1976 (Box 29)
  - Frison, George C., 1976-1995 (Box 29)
  - Funk, Robert E., 1976-1988 (Box 29)
  - Furst, Peter T., 1979-1980 (Box 29)
  - F -- Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  - Galloway, Patricia, 1983-1996 (Box 29)
  - Gardner, William M., 1977-1982 (Box 29)
  - Garland, Elizabeth, 1977-1985 (Box 29)
  - Garn, Stanley, 1976-1996 (Box 29)
  - George, Richard L., 1981-1995 (Box 29)
  - Gibson, Jon L., 1976-1994 (Box 29)
  - Giles, Eugene, 1976-1983 (Box 29)
  - Givens, Douglas R., 1984-1993 (Box 29)
  - Glenn, James R., 1976-1985 (Box 29)
  - Goad, Sharon, 1976-1978 (Box 29)
  - Gonzalez, Nancie L., 1977-1979 (Box 29)
  - Goodenough, Ward, 1976-1983 (Box 29)
  - Goodyear, Albert C., 1980-1992 (Box 29)
  - Gorenflo, Larry, 1984-1987 (Box 29)
  - Gradwohl, David M., 1976 (Box 29)
  - Gramly, Michael, 1985-1995 (Box 29)
  - Greber, N'omi, 1976-1994; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Green, William, 1985-1995 (Box 29)
  - Griffin, David M. and Sally, 1984-1986 (Box 29)
  - Grubb, Thomas C., 1977-1990 (Box 29)
  - Guthe, Alfred K., 1976-1979 (Box 29)
  - G -- Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  - Haag, William G., 1976-1995 (Box 29)
  - Hadleigh West, Frederick, 1977-1989 (Box 29)
  - Hall, Robert L., 1976-1993 (Box 29)
  - Hally, David J., 1986-1994 (Box 29)
  - Hard, Robert A., 1977-1978 (Box 29)
  - Haury, Emil W., 1976-1984 (Box 29)
  - Haynes, Vance, 1984-1993 (Box 29)
  - Heilman, James M., 1976-1989 (Box 29)
  - Helm, June, 1977-1982 (Box 29)
  - Hester, Thomas R., 1976-1978 (Box 29)
  - Hofman, Jack L., 1979 (Box 29)
  - Holley, George R., 1990-1991 (Box 29)
  - Holloway, R. Ross, 1976-1978 (Box 30)
  - Holwitz, Stanley, 1976-1977 (Box 30)
  - Hopper, Doris, 1976-1986 (Box 30)
  - Horvath, Sally, 1986-1997 (Box 30)
  - Hurley, William H., 1976-1979 (Box 30)
  - Hurt, Wesley R., 1977-1983 (Box 30)
  - H -- Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Isaac, Barry L., 1976-1979 (Box 30)
  - I -- Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Jackson, Ed, 1982-1994 (Box 30)
  - Jelinek, Arthur J., 1976-1977 (Box 30)
  - Jelks, Edward B., 1976-1985 (Box 30)
  - Jennings, Jesse D., 1976-1983 (Box 30)
  - Jeter, Marvin, 1980-1997 (Box 30)
  - Johnson, Ann M., 1981-1993 (Box 30)
  - Johnson, Gregory, 1976-1991 (Box 30)
  - Johnston, Richard B., 1979-1985 (Box 30)
  - Jones, Douglas, 1976-1986 (Box 30)
  - J -- Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Keel, Bennie C., 1976-1982 (Box 30)
  - Kellar, James H., 1977-1982 (Box 30)
  - Kelly, John E., 1985-1995 (Box 30)
  - Kidder, Tristam R., 1987-1997 (Box 30)
  - King, J.C.H., 1984-1988 (Box 30)
  - Knight, Vernon J., 1978-1990 (Box 30)
  - Knudson, Ruthann, 1982-1983 (Box 30)
  - Kraft, Herbert C., 1976-1986 (Box 30)
  - Krogman, William M., 1976-1978 (Box 30)
  - K -- Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Lamberg-Karlovsky, C.C., 1976-1979 (Box 30)
  - Larson, Lewis, 1995-1997 (Box 30)
  - Laughlin, William S., 1976-1978 (Box 30)
  - Lechtman, Heather, 1975-1981 (Box 30)
  - Lehman, Edward J., 1976-1977 (Box 30)
  - Lewis, R. Barry, 1983-1991 (Box 30)
  - Lopick, Jill, 1983-1993 (Box 30)
  - Lovis, William, 1978-1981 (Box 30)
  - Lucy, Charles L., 1982 (Box 30)
  - Luedtke, Barbara, 1976-1979 (Box 30)
  - Lynch, Thomas F., 1976-1977 (Box 30)
  - Lyon, Edwin A., 1975-1992 (Box 30)
  - L -- Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - MacNeish, Richard S., 1976-1988 (Box 30)
  - Madison, James H., 1986-1993 (Box 30)
  - Mainfort, Robert C., 1982-1995 (Box 30)
  - Mango, Susan, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Mangold, William L., 1984 (Box 30)
  - Marlowe, Gregory J., 1975-1988 (Box 30)
  - Marquardt, William H., 1977-1993 (Box 30)
  - Marshall, Richard A., 1978-1982 (Box 30)
  - Martin, Terrance J., 1986-1996 (Box 30)
  - Mason, Carol, 1976-1992 (Box 30)
  - Maybury-Lewis, David, 1977-1981 (Box 30)
  - McGimsey, Charles R., III, 1983-1984 (Box 30)
  - McKendry, John, 1988-1991 (Box 30)
  - McMillan, R. Bruce, 1976-1987 (Box 30)
  - McNutt, Charles H., 1976-1996 (Box 30)
  - Meggers, Betty Evans, 1979-1997 (Box 30)
  - Mehrer, Mark, 1982-1983 (Box 30)
  - Meighan, Clement, 1976-1980 (Box 30)
  - Meltzer, David J., 1981-1996 (Box 30)
  - Milanich, Jerald T., 1977-1992 (Box 30)
  - Milisauskas, Sarunas, 1979-1986 (Box 30)
  - Milner, George, 1983-1991 (Box 30)
  - Moratto, Michael J., 1976-1980 (Box 30)
  - Morgan, William, 1978-1979 (Box 30)
  - Morse, Dan F., 1976-1990 (Box 30)
  - Muller, Jon, 1978-1989 (Box 31)
  - Munson, Cheryl Ann, 1976-1981 (Box 31)
  - Munson, Patrick, 1976-1988 (Box 31)
  - Murphy, James L., 1981-1985 (Box 31)
  - M -- Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Neighbors, Wayne, 1980-1981 (Box 31)
  - Neitzel, Robert S. (Stuart), 1976 (Box 31)
  - Neuman, Robert W., 1976-1994 (Box 31)
  - Nishimura, Masae, 1979-1984 (Box 31)
  - N -- Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - O'Brien, Michael J., 1987-1996 (Box 31)
  - O'Brien, Patricia J., 1979-1983 (Box 31)
  - O'Shea, John M., 1988-1996 (Box 31)
  - Oehler, Charles, 1978-1983 (Box 31)
  - Oestreicher, David M., 1996 (Box 31)
  - Orr, Carol, 1983-1986 (Box 31)
  - Osmundsen, Lita, 1976-1980 (Box 31)
  - Otto, Martha Potter, 1976-1996 (Box 31)
  - O -- Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Parsons, Jeffrey R., 1984-1995 (Box 31)
  - Pauketat, Timothy, 1982-1995 (Box 31)
  - Peebles, Christopher, 1977-1988 (Box 31)
  - Perino, Gregory H., 1976-1991 (Box 31)
  - Peru, Don, 1981-1986 (Box 31)
  - Phillips, James, 1978-1982 (Box 31)
  - Phillips, Philip, 1976-1987 (Box 31)
  - Pickenpaugh, Tom, 1992-1994 (Box 31)
  - Porter, James, 1976-1985 (Box 31)
  - Powell, Mary, 1983-1991 (Box 31)
  - Power, Philip H., 1988-1993 (Box 31)
  - Pratt, Peter P., 1976-1980 (Box 31)
  - Price, James E., 1976-1981 (Box 31)
  - Prufer, Olaf H., 1976-1993 (Box 31)
  - P -- Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Q -- Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Rackerby, Frank, 1976 (Box 31)
  - Rapp, George, 1976-1980 (Box 31)
  - Rice, Don S., 1992-1993 (Box 31)
  - Riley, Carroll L., 1979-1980 (Box 31)
  - Riley, Tom, 1978-1992 (Box 31)
  - Ritchie, William A., 1976-1988 (Box 31)
  - Romain, William F., 1979-1993 (Box 31)
  - Roosevelt, Anna C., 1980-1990; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Rouse, Irving, 1977-1980 (Box 31)
  - R -- Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Sackett, Jim, 1976-1978 (Box 31)
  - Schock, Jack M., 1976 (Box 31)
  - Schuyler, Robert L., 1977-1981 (Box 31)
  - Seeman, Mark F., 1980-1992 (Box 31)
  - Shaffer, Lynda, 1991 (Box 31)
  - Shannon, George Ward, Jr., 1980-1994 (Box 31)
  - Shenkel, J. Richard, 1976-1983 (Box 31)
  - Shine, Carolyn R., 1975-1978 (Box 31)
  - Shott, Michael, 1986-1995 (Box 31)
  - Simco, Nancy D., 1986-1987 (Box 31)
  - Simmons, Edward M., 1976-1990 (Box 31)
  - Simmons, Lanier, 1976-1984 (Box 31)
  - Sinopoli, Carla, 1986-1989 (Box 31)
  - Smith, Bruce D., 1976-1991 (Box 32)
  - Snider, Edwin W., 1977-1987 (Box 32)
  - Snow, Dean R., 1976-1996 (Box 32)
  - Soffer, Olga, 1976-1985 (Box 32)
  - Spaulding, Albert C., 1976-1981 (Box 32)
  - Speiden, Sandra, 1990-1991 (Box 32)
  - Spence, Michael, 1977-1984 (Box 32)
  - Speth, John D., 1977-1989 (Box 32)
  - Spielmann, Katherine, 1982 (Box 32)
  - Spuhler, J.N., 1985-1986 (Box 32)
  - Stephenson, Robert L., 1975-1982 (Box 32)
  - Steponaitis, Vincas, 1977-1995 (Box 32)
  - Stock, Leon M., 1976 (Box 32)
  - Stoltman, James B., 1977-1991 (Box 32)
  - Stothers, Dave, 1976-1979 (Box 32)
  - Stresser Pan, Guy, 1978-1988 (Box 32)
  - Struever, Stuart, 1978-1984 (Box 32)
  - Sturtevant, William C., 1977-1979 (Box 32)
  - Swartz, B.K., 1976-1977 (Box 32)
  - Sweeney, Lynne, 1976-1977 (Box 32)
  - S -- Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Tandarich, John, 1976 (Box 32)
  - Taylor, R.E., 1976-1994 (Box 32)
  - Taylor, William E., 1976-1994 (Box 32)
  - Thurman, Melburn D., 1975-1979 (Box 32)
  - Toth, Alan, 1976-1978 (Box 32)
  - Trigger, Bruce G., 1976-1977 (Box 32)
  - Trinkley, Michael, 1976-1980 (Box 32)
  - T -- Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - U -- Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - V -- Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - Wagner, Gail E., 1980-1984 (Box 32)
  - Walthall, John A., 1975-1997 (Box 32)
  - Ward, H. Trawick, 1980-1984 (Box 32)
  - Watson, Patty Jo, 1976-1994 (Box 32)
  - Webb, Clarence H., 1976-1985 (Box 32)
  - Welch, Paul D., 1984-1996 (Box 32)
  - Wendorf, Fred, 1976-1994 (Box 32)
  - Werner, Eliot, 1978-1990 (Box 32)
  - Wesler, Kit W., 1983-1991 (Box 32)
  - Wiant, Michael, 1981-1985 (Box 32)
  - Willey, Gordon R., 1975-1987 (Box 32)
  - Williams, Stephen, 1976-1997; 3 folders (Box 32)
    (3 of 12 folders)
  - Williams, Stephen, 1976-1997; 9 folders (Box 33)
    (9 of 12 folders)
  - Willis, Chip, 1986-1991 (Box 33)
  - Wobst, H. Martin, 1976-1979 (Box 33)
  - Wojcick, Judith C., 1976 (Box 33)
  - Wood, W. Raymond, 1976-1979 (Box 33)
  - Woodcock, William E., 1976-1987 (Box 33)
  - Woodhams, Robert E., 1977-1978 (Box 33)
  - Woods, William I., 1986-1993 (Box 33)
  - Wright, Henry T., 1980-1997 (Box 33)
  - Wright, James V., 1976-1978 (Box 33)
  - W -- Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Y -- Miscellaneous (Box 33)
  - Unidentified (Box 33)
- Radiocarbon Lab, 1949-1972
  The Radiocarbon Laboratory series, 1949-1972 (15 linear feet), documents the activities of the Radiocarbon Laboratory, in operation at the University of Michigan from 1949 to 1970 as Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project #6. The series is held in five subseries: Correspondence, Datasheet Notebooks, Lab Administration, Research, and Card Files. (Additional information on the laboratory and related research projects can be found in the Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project record group, also available at the Bentley Historical Library.)
  - Correspondence
    The Correspondence subseries consists mainly of correspondence between the lab's administrators and research assistants and those who sent specimens to be analyzed. The subseries is divided into two chronological spans, 1949-1960 and 1961-1971, with the correspondence within each sorted alphabetically by the name of the correspondent. While the correspondence in this series is almost exclusively focused on the activities of the lab and the dating of specimens, there is some material on other subjects and a great deal of overlap between the correspondents in this subseries and those in the larger Correspondence, 1930-1975 series. A substantial portion of the correspondence in this subseries was not written by Griffin; other writers include lab administrators H.R. Crane and Volney Jones, and research assistants Alan McPherron, Ingrid Christensen, Arthur Jelinek, David M. Griffin (Griffin's son), Roscoe Wilmeth, and Jeffrey Parsons.
    - 1949-1960
      - A-Z, 27 folders (Box 34)
    - 1961-1971
      - A-Be, 4 folders (Box 34)
      - Bi-T, 24 folders (Box 35)
      - V-Z, 5 folders (Box 36)
  - Datasheet Notebooks
    The Datasheets Notebooks subseries contains the contents of three-ring notebooks that held individual datasheets of information on samples submitted to the Radiocarbon Laboratory. From 1956 until the lab's closure, a listing of dated specimens was submitted to and published periodically in the journal Radiocarbon. Each listing was referred to as "Michigan" followed by a sequential Roman numeral. This subseries contains the datasheets for nearly all of these published listings, though datasheets for samples published in listings before Michigan XI were not filed together. Often, however, the earlier datasheets have a handwritten Roman numeral on them indicating in which listing they appeared. Datasheets for samples that were never published can be found in the folders labeled "Datasheets Impossible to Publish."
    - Published Samples M-286 -- M-999 (Box 36)
    - Published Samples M-1000 -- M-1311 (Box 36)
    - Published Samples M-1312 -- M-1567 (Box 36)
    - Samples for Michigan XI (Box 36)
    - Samples for Michigan XII (Box 36)
    - Samples for Michigan XIII and XIV (Box 36)
    - Samples for Michigan XV (Box 37)
    - Samples Not Yet Run (Box 37)
    - Datasheets Impossible to Publish (Box 37)
  - Lab Administration
    The Lab Administration subseries is comprised of materials related to the day-to-day administration of the lab and specimen testing. It includes information on billing, procedures, specimen lists, the running file for specimens, and forms. A brief history of the lab up to 1965, written by H.R. Crane, is included in the folder titled "Funding."
    - Background Information, circa 1949-1960 (Box 37)
    - Billings, 1957-1960 (Box 37)
      (from Physics Department)
    - C-14 Punch Card Key, undated (Box 37)
    - Date Lists from Lab, 1963-1969 (Box 37)
    - Forms and Handouts, undated (Box 37)
    - Funding, 1949-1968 (Box 37)
    - Procedures, undated (Box 37)
    - Radiocarbon
      - Contributor Instructions, 1964-1970 (Box 37)
      - Reprints of Michigan I through XV, 1956-1972 (Box 37)
    - Radiocarbon Dating Committee, 1949-1952 (Box 37)
    - Radiocarbon Symposium, 1952 (Box 37)
    - Report, 1956 (Box 37)
    - Reprint Requests, 1952-1958 (Box 37)
    - Sample Preparation Data from Lab, 1964-1970 (Box 37)
    - Specimen Lists, undated (Box 37)
  - Research
    The Research subseries contains information on an ongoing research project that, while separate from the Radiocarbon Laboratory, drew on some of the same personnel and expertise. Funded from 1956 to 1965 as Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project #132 under the working title "Study of Radioactivity Levels in Prehistoric Materials," this project sought to obtain equipment and develop methods for measuring radioactivity in specimens to apply to the problems of dating and identification. Over the years, the project was directed by F.P. Thieme (1956-1958), James Griffin (1958-1961), and Arthur Jelinek (1961-1965), and employed several research assistants, including Jelinek (1957-1958), Lewis Binford (1958-1960), James Fitting (1961-1963), and Charles Cleland (1962). At its culmination, a series of reports of the project's findings were published as University of Michigan Anthropological Papers No. 25. The subseries contains proposals, correspondence, research reports, datasheets, and administrative materials related to the project, as well as a draft of a Binford manuscript not included in the Anthropological Papers volume.
    - Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project (MMPP) #132
      - "Analysis of the Radioactive Properties of Bone Specimens from the Smith Site, Delaware County, Oklahoma," by Lewis Binford, 1960 (Box 37)
      - Correspondence, 1956-1964 (Box 37)
      - Juntunen, undated (Box 37)
      - Lab Reports, undated (Box 37)
      - Personnel, 1958-1963 (Box 37)
      - Procedure Manual, 1963 (Box 37)
      - Progress Reports, 1957-1959 (Box 37)
      - Project Administration, 1956-1963 (Box 37)
      - Proportional Flow Counter, undated (Box 37)
        (Arthur Jelinek)
      - Reports (of results, by Lewis Binford), 1958-1960 (Box 37)
      - Reports and Papers, 1957-1958 (Box 37)
        (of results, by Arthur Jelinek)
      - Reports and Worksheets, [1961-1963] (Box 37)
        (of results, by James Fitting)
  - Card Files, 1949-1970
    The Card Files subseries contains index cards for various organizations of the Radiocarbon Laboratory sample catalogue, a set of punch cards, and geographically-arranged cards for radiocarbon dates obtained from labs throughout the world. Organizations of the catalogue include samples by numerical order, samples by investigator, samples by geographic area, and an association file providing information on related locations and publications in which samples appeared.
    - Catalogue by Sample Number, M-1 through M-906 (Box 38)
    - Catalogue by Investigator, A-Z (Box 39)
    - M-2 -- M-1175 Association File (Box 39)
    - Catalogue by Geographic Area
      - Upper Mississippi Valley and Great Lakes
        - Illinois (Box 40)
        - Indiana (Box 40)
        - Iowa (Box 40)
        - Kentucky (Box 40)
        - Michigan (Box 40)
        - Minnesota (Box 40)
        - Missouri (Box 40)
        - Ohio (Box 40)
        - Wisconsin (Box 40)
      - Lower Mississippi Valley and Southeast
        - Alabama, Arkansas, Georgia, Florida (Box 40)
        - Kentucky, Louisiana, Maryland, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, Oklahoma (Box 40)
      - Northeastern U.S. and Canada
        - Maine, New Jersey, New York, Massachusetts (Box 40)
        - Pennsylvania, Rhode Island (Box 40)
        - Canada (Box 40)
      - U.S. Great Plains
        - Kansas, Nebraska, S. Dakota, N. Dakota (Box 40)
      - Western United States
        - Arizona, California, Colorado (Box 40)
        - Idaho, Montana, Nevada, New Mexico (Box 40)
        - Oregon, Texas, Utah, Washington, Wyoming (Box 40)
      - Arctic, Northwest Territories, Greenland (Box 40)
      - Mexico and South America
        - Mexico (Box 40)
        - Meso-South America (Box 40)
      - Far East and Pacific (Box 40)
      - Antarctic (Box 40)
      - Africa and Old World
        - Europe (Box 40)
        - Near East and Africa
    - Ceramics File (Box 40)
    - Radiocarbon Date Files (Box 41)
      (includes dates from other labs)
      - Northeast U.S.
        - New England (Box 41)
        - New York (Box 41)
        - Middle Atlantic (Box 41)
        - West Virginia, Pennsylvania (Box 41)
        - Pennsylvania (Box 41)
      - Upper Great Lakes
        - Michigan (Box 41)
        - Wisconsin (Box 41)
        - Minnesota (Box 41)
      - Ohio-Middle Mississippi
        - Ohio (Box 41)
        - Kentucky (Box 41)
        - Indiana (Box 41)
        - Illinois (Box 41)
        - Missouri (Box 41)
        - Iowa (Box 41)
      - Southeast U.S.
        - Carolina (North and South) (Box 41)
        - Tennessee (Box 41)
        - Alabama (Box 41)
        - Georgia (Box 41)
        - Florida (Box 41)
      - Southern Mississippi-Southern Plains
        - Mississippi (Box 41)
        - Louisiana-Arkansas (Box 41)
        - Oklahoma (Box 41)
        - Texas (Box 41)
      - Northern and Central Plains
        - South Dakota (Box 42)
        - Kansas (Box 42)
        - Nebraska (Box 42)
      - Southwest U.S.
        - New Mexico (Box 42)
        - Arizona (Box 42)
        - Nevada (Box 42)
        - Utah (Box 42)
      - Rocky Mountains
        - Colorado (Box 42)
        - Montana (Box 42)
        - Idaho (Box 42)
        - Wyoming (Box 42)
      - Great Basin (Box 42)
      - Pacific Coast
        - Washington, Oregon (Box 42)
        - California (Box 42)
      - Southern Canada (Box 42)
      - Mexico
        - Northeast (Box 43)
        - Northwest (Box 43)
        - Central (Box 43)
        - Southern (Box 43)
      - Central America
        - Guatemala, British Honduras, El Salvador (Box 43)
        - Costa Rica, Panama, Nicaragua (Box 43)
      - Orinoco, Guiana, Antilles (Box 43)
      - Northern Andes (Box 43)
      - Central Andes
        - Peru
        - Bolivia (Box 43)
      - Amazon Basin and Brazil (Box 43)
      - Southern South America (Box 43)
      - Northwest Europe
        - Belgium (Box 44)
        - Netherlands, Belgium (Box 44)
      - British Isles
        - Great Britain (Box 44)
        - Ireland (Box 44)
      - Scandinavia
        - Iceland (Box 44)
        - Norway (Box 44)
        - Denmark (Box 44)
        - Sweden (Box 44)
      - Southwest Europe
        - France (Box 45)
        - Spain, Portugal (Box 45)
        - Mediterranean (Box 45)
      - Mediterranean (Box 45)
      - Central Europe
        - Switzerland (Box 45)
        - Germany (Box 45)
        - Czechoslovakia, Austria, Hungary, Poland (Box 45)
      - South-Central Europe (Italy) (Box 45)
      - Southeast Europe (Box 45)
      - U.S.S.R. (Box 45)
      - Soviet Asia (Box 45)
      - South Asia
        - Afghanistan (Box 46)
        - India, Pakistan, Nepal (Box 46)
        - Southeast Asia (Box 46)
      - Far East (Box 46)
      - West Africa